Contact

+972525344907 (Mobile) sergey@bolshchikov.net

www.linkedin.com/in/bolshchikov (LinkedIn)

bolshchikov.net (Personal)

Top Skills

JavaScript
Web Development
Software Development

Languages

Rust (Elementary)
Python (Professional Working)
Ruby (Elementary)

Honors-Awards

Opportunity Grant from Public Affairs Section of US Embassy

University Exhibition of Students Inventions and Software

Publications

Modeling and Simulation-based Systems Engineering Handbook

Visualizing the Dynamics of Conceptual Behavior Models: The Vivid OPM Scene Player

Patents

Computer-Aided Information System "ECHO"

Sergey Bolshchikov

VP R&D at Swiftt (We're hiring!)

Summary

I have a proven experience of designing, building products from ground up; managing development under real user traffic with 100k requests traffic.

I know how to build and scale a team who will continue building products.

I know how to mentor each team member to teach their own next milestone.

Experience

Swiftt

VP R&D

March 2020 - Present (2 months)

Tel Aviv, Israel

Swiftt is a modern enterprise procurement SaaS.

Orbs

Solutions Architect

February 2019 - March 2020 (1 year 2 months)

Tel Aviv Area, Israel

- Leading the strategic development of potential use cases utilizing Orbs.
- Building the development of Proof of Concepts
- Conducting educational webinars

Wix.com

4 years 6 months

Engineering Manager

April 2018 - December 2018 (9 months)

Tel Aviv, Israel

Being engineering manager at Wix for the Front End Engineering group our goal is to create the place for over 350 front-end developers can grow, deliver and excel!.

This includes the range of different spheres like recruitment, onboarding, education, communication, branding, engineering and more.

Team Lead

June 2016 - May 2018 (2 years)

Israel

Growing a team from 5 to 12 developers. Together we've built and design a new back office platform that hosts over 30 applications.

Technical Lead

June 2015 - June 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Tel Aviv Area, Israel

Design and implement invoices application under the family of CRM products.

Software Engineer

July 2014 - June 2015 (1 year)

Design and implement from ground up the news feed cms.

Refactor news feed app.

You Gotta Love Frontend Conference

Co-Founder

August 2014 - December 2018 (4 years 5 months)

Tel Aviv, Israel

Founding the largest top-notch quality conference for Front-end developers in the Middle East and East Europe.

New Prolmage LTD

2 years 2 months

Senior Front-End Engineer

July 2013 - July 2014 (1 year 1 month)

Israel

Developing application framework for the large-scale real-time application with the use of design patterns (mediator, facade, module), requirejs, web sockets, Ember.js, SVG and Canvas technologies.

Building automated testing system with NodeJS, PhantomJS and Jasmine for unit-testing.

Writing open-source Ember.js components library.

Frontend Engineer

June 2012 - June 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Israel

Design and implement the framework for the rich web client application.

Extensive research of Javascript MVC frameworks, GUI frameworks, Singlepage application.

http://www.slideshare.net/bolshchikov/js-web-app-essentials

Education

Technion - Israel Institute of Technology MSc, Information Systems · (2009 - 2013)

Ural State Technical University
Engineer's degree, Information Systems in Medicine · (2004 - 2009)

Music School # 4 Diploma, Piano · (1994 - 2003)